hollandandbarrett.com 2018-01-28

# Holland & Barrett - the UK’s Leading Health Retailer> Privacy & cookie policy

At Holland & Barrett we make every effort to ensure we protect your personal information.

This site, www.hollandandbarrett.com (the "Website") is owned and operated by Holland & Barrett Retail Limited. In this Privacy Policy (“Policy”), the terms "Holland & Barrett", "we", "us" and "our" mean Holland & Barrett Retail Limited and other companies within the same group, and include their terrestrial stores and the Website. 

This Policy, in conjunction with our Terms and Conditions, explains how Holland & Barrett may use the information we collect about you, as well as the rights you have over any personal information we hold about you.

Please read this Policy and our Terms and Conditions carefully; by accessing the Website you confirm to have understood and agreed to them.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com](mailto:customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com) or write to us at Customer Services, Holland & Barrett Retail Limited, Samuel Ryder House, Barling Way, Eliot Park, Nuneaton, Warwickshire, CV10 7RH.

## **Information we collect**

We collect information about you (such as your name, email address, phone number shipping address, transaction details and credit card information) when you:

  * visit the Website;
  * register on or buy products on the Website;
  * use your rewards for life card;
  * take part in our promotions, competitions, customer surveys and questionnaires; or
  * contact us via e-mail, phone or letter.

We may choose to add to this data by collecting information from other sources such as Information Service Companies. This additional data helps us to check the accuracy of the data we hold about you and to send you the most relevant offers and promotions.

## **How we use your information**

We collect your personal information to help Holland & Barrett better understand you and to enable us to personalise your experience with Holland & Barrett, including offers, promotions and services to meet your needs. We use your information to:

  * personalise our services, offers and promotions to you;
  * operate your online account and your rewards for life account;
  * process your online orders and in-store purchases;
  * tell you about important changes to Holland & Barrett;
  * develop and improve our products and services;
  * manage promotions, competitions, customer surveys and questionnaires; and
  * check and verify your identity, and prevent or detect crime.

(In performing such checks, your information may be disclosed to credit reference agencies who keep a record of that information, but these are not credit checks and your credit rating will not be affected.) 

From time to time, we may also share your information with carefully selected partners to enable them to help us provide you with the best service from Holland & Barrett. However, we will never give permission for any of these partners to contact you directly with marketing information unless we have your consent and all our parties adhere to strict data protection policies. 

## **Rewards for life Information**

We access the information recorded through the use of your rewards for life card to help us improve our service to you and to make our communications more relevant.

## **Marketing and Customer Research**

With your prior agreement, we may contact you by email, post, SMS or phone:

  * with details of offers and information about Holland & Barrett products or services;
  * with offers and information about products or services from selected partners, or for customer research e.g. to help improve our services, products, stores or the Website.

It is entirely your choice if you wish to receive or not receive this information. However, if you tell us that you don’t want to receive marketing information from us this, will mean that you won’t get details of great offers or promotions that may be of interest to you.

You may choose to no longer receive marketing information from us by:

  * amending your options within the "Your Details" section of "My Account" on the Website;
  * clicking on the "unsubscribe" link on the bottom of any of our e-mails to opt of email communications;
  * amending your options within the Holland & Barrett Mobile App;
  * calling us on 0370 606 6606; or
  * writing to us at Holland & Barrett Retail Limited, Samuel Ryder House, Barling Way, Eliot Park, Nuneaton, Warwickshire, CV10 7RH.

## **COOKIES**

To help you to better understand the cookies that we use on the Website we use a classification that was developed by the International Chamber of Commerce UK.  This explains more about which cookies we use, why we use them, and the functionality you will lose if you decide you don't want to have them on your device.

### **What is a cookie?**

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your personal computer, mobile or other device when you visit a website. This information is then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognise a user's device.

There are two types of cookies that can be used:

**Persistent cookies** \- these cookies remain on a user's device for the period of time specified in the cookie. They are activated each time that the user visits the website that created that particular cookie.

**Session cookies** \- these cookies allow website operators to link the actions of a user during a browser session. A browser session starts when a user opens the browser window and finishes when they close the browser window. Session cookies are created temporarily. Once you close the browser, all session cookies are deleted.

Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improving your user experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.

You can find more information about cookies at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

### **Cookies used on the Website**

A list of all the cookies used on the Website by category is set out below.

### **Strictly necessary cookies**

**These cookies enable services you have specifically asked for. For the types of cookies that are strictly necessary, no consent is required.**

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the Website. Without these cookies services you have asked for, such as shopping baskets or e-billing, cannot be provided.

### **Analysis cookies**

**These cookies collect _anonymous_ information on the pages visited. By using the Website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.**

These cookies collect information about how visitors use the Website; for instance, which pages visitors go to most often, which pages they go to next and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don't collect information that identifies a visitor. All the information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how the Website works.

### **Functionality cookies**

**These cookies remember choices you make to improve your experience. By using the Website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.**

These cookies allow the Website to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customise. They may also be used to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

### **Targeting or advertising cookies**

**These cookies collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising relevant to you and your interests.**

These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with our permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organisations such as advertisers. Quite often targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organisation.

## **Behavioural advertising and online privacy**

Behavioural advertising enables retailers to display adverts to you on the web based on the products and retailers that you have previously visited.  A guide to behavioural advertising and online privacy has been produced by the internet advertising industry which can be found at [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). The guide contains an explanation of the self-regulatory scheme to allow you greater control of the advertising you see.

We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with relevant online display advertising tailored to your interests. To opt out of our cookies used for this online advertising, click [here](http://dtmc.hollandandbarrett.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=61490&cname=Holland%20And%20Barrett&cmagic=e2db1b&clogo=61490.png&loc=us&lang=en-us)

## **Using browser settings to manage cookies**

You are able to use the settings within your browser to control the cookies that can be placed onto your computer.  The ‘Help’ menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether.

However, cookies are essential to allow you to take advantage of some of the Website's features, so we recommend that you leave them turned on. For example, if you block or otherwise reject cookies you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Basket, proceed to Checkout, or use any of our products and services that require you to Sign in i.e. to track your Rewards for Life points. If you leave cookies turned on, remember to sign off when you finish using a shared computer.

## **Log Files**

As is true of most web sites, we and our third party tracking-utility partner gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. 

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the Website, to track users’ movements around the Website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

## **Social Media Features and Widgets**

Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Website. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## **Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). If you have any questions regarding security you can contact us at [customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com](mailto:customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com)

## **Disclosing your information**

We will never disclose your information to anyone outside the Holland & Barrett group of companies except where we have your consent; where we are required or permitted to do so by law, such as when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process; where other companies who provide a service to us as part of our order process require that data i.e. delivery companies, payment providers; or companies who send out email communications on our behalf; or where they are successors in title to our business.  We will never share your data with other companies for marketing purposes. 

## **Other websites**

The Website may contain links to other sites which are outside our control and not covered by this Policy. The operators of these sites may collect information from you that will be used by them in accordance with their policy, which may differ from ours.

## **Public Forums**

Our Website offers publicly accessible blogs, community forums or reviews. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com](mailto:customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## **Accessing your information**

To obtain a copy of the information we hold about you, write to: Data Protection Officer, Holland & Barrett Retail Limited, Samuel Ryder House, Barling Way, Eliot Park, Nuneaton, Warwickshire, CV10 7RH enclosing a cheque or postal order for £10 payable to "Holland & Barrett Retail Limited". Please confirm your Rewards for Life number and any details to help us identify and locate your information. If any of the details are incorrect, let us know and we will amend them.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com](mailto:customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## **Changes to our policy**

This Policy replaces all previous versions and is correct as of **29th July 2016**.  We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a prominent notice on this Website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page and our Website for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## **Contacting us**

If you have any queries, please contact us at [customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com](mailto:customerservices@hollandandbarrett.com)  or writing to us at Holland & Barrett Retail Limited, Samuel Ryder House, Barling Way, Eliot Park, Nuneaton, Warwickshire, CV10 7RH
